<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="514" moduleid="3058" modulename="forum" contextid="3858">
  <forum id="514">
    <type>qanda</type>
    <name>Open Explorer</name>
    <intro>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission&lt;/strong&gt;: As a group, identify 10 unique OER that can be used for open teaching in science and 10 instructional strategies or approaches to open teaching that involve students reusing, remixing, or revising OER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Each participant must contribute at least one OER and one open strategy to the group mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reply to the Open Explorer discussion thread below to share your OER.  In your forum post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Identify one OER and one open strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Specify which Rs you’re leveraging with the proposed strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;Share what practices you think can be developed with the approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Once the mission is accomplished (you have completed the activity), you will be able to view other participants’ responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;This mission is best accomplished by a Web search for OER and for resources created by the open community about teaching with OER. Use key words such as open pedagogy, OER instructional strategies, OER teaching practices, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;OER of all types might provide important clues. Lesson plans might be particularly helpful. Use what you learned in &lt;em&gt;Course 1: Open Your Classroom with OER&lt;/em&gt; to search for OER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;The OER could be related to any topic, but when you post you must specify how they relate to science instruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <assessed>0</assessed>
    <assesstimestart>0</assesstimestart>
    <assesstimefinish>0</assesstimefinish>
    <scale>-19</scale>
    <maxbytes>512000</maxbytes>
    <maxattachments>9</maxattachments>
    <forcesubscribe>0</forcesubscribe>
    <trackingtype>1</trackingtype>
    <rsstype>0</rsstype>
    <rssarticles>0</rssarticles>
    <timemodified>1534175636</timemodified>
    <warnafter>0</warnafter>
    <blockafter>0</blockafter>
    <blockperiod>0</blockperiod>
    <completiondiscussions>0</completiondiscussions>
    <completionreplies>0</completionreplies>
    <completionposts>1</completionposts>
    <displaywordcount>0</displaywordcount>
    <lockdiscussionafter>0</lockdiscussionafter>
    <discussions>
    </discussions>
    <subscriptions>
    </subscriptions>
    <digests>
    </digests>
    <readposts>
    </readposts>
    <trackedprefs>
    </trackedprefs>
    <poststags>
    </poststags>
  </forum>
</activity>